Earlier, we saw resource records inside a
DNS server.
You may, however, at times need to look up
some DNS information on an entity, and you
may not have a DNS server in front of you.
For this, we can use the nslookup command.
I have opened a command prompt, and I am going
to type, nslookup, and select the Enter key
on the keyboard.
The result is a DNS server address to which
I am connected.
Doing this also puts us in nslookup mode,
where we can look up DNS information on other
entities.
For instance, if I type, google.com, and select
the Enter key on the keyboard, I have DNS
information from Google.
By default, nslookup returns A type records.
However, let's say I want to see the mail
exchange record for an entity.
I will type, set type=mx, to have nslookup
look up mail exchange records.
Then, I will type, google.com, again, and
this time, I see mail exchange records.
When I'm done using nslookup, I can just type,
exit, select the Enter key on the keyboard,
and exit nslookup.